niagara.edu 2006-06-19

# Niagara University - Privacy Statement

1\. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personally identification is collected from you through the Web site.

2\. The organization collecting the information.

3\. How the information is used.

4\. With whom the information may be shared.

5\. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.

6\. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Niagara University control.

7\. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

Niagara University is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways other than what is disclosed in this statement. Niagara University collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site.  

****

**Registration**  
In order to use parts of this Web site, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration, a user is required to give his/her contact information (such as name and e-mail address). This information is used to inform the user about the services he/she is interested in. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as ethnicity and gender), and unique identifiers (such as social security number), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site.

**  
Order**  
We request information from the user on our order form. Here a user must provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customers’ orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about him/her. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes his/her browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, which saves time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, he/she may still use our site, but will have limited usage of our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Links  
**This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we [NIAGARA UNIVERSITY] are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when leaving our site to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Newsletters  
**If a user wishes to subscribe to our online newsletters, we ask for contact information such as name and e-mail address.

**Surveys & Contests  
**From time to time, our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

**Tell-A-Friend  
**If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend’s name and e-mail address. NIAGARA UNIVERSITY will automatically send the friend a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit the site. NIAGARA UNIVERSITY stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail. The friend may contact NIAGARA UNIVERSITY at webmaster@niagara.edu to request the removal of this information from the university’s database.

**Security  
**This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, your information is protected both online and off-line. When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to unlocked, or open, when you are just “surfing”.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also take precautions to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, including the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, and any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers’ information is protected. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment, behind a locked cage. If you have any questions about the security at our Web site, you can send an email to webmaster@niagara.edu.

****

**  
Site and Service Updates  
**We also send the user site and service announcement updates. Members are not able to unsubscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regard to issues relating to their account via e-mail or phone.

**Correction/Updating Personal Information:  
**If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user’s personal data. This can usually be done at the member information page **** or by e-mailing our customer support **.** [Some sites may also provide telephone or postal mail options for updating **** or correcting **** personal information].

**Choice/Opt-out  
**Our users are given the opportunity to “opt-out” of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site when we ask for the information. For example, our order form has an “opt-out” mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don’t want any marketing material, can keep their e-mail address off of our lists.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from our partners may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the e-mail or e-mail us at webmaster@niagara.edu [Some sites are able to offer opt-out mechanisms on member information pages and also supply a telephone or postal option as a way to opt-out.]

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party.

**Notification of Changes  
**If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our home page so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. Users will be notified if personally identifiable information may be used in a manner other than that stated at the time it was collected, and will be able to “opt-out” of this different usage. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
